findsomeone.co.nz 2015-05-04

# Privacy Policy | FindSomeone

### Privacy Policy

#### Your right to privacy is of the utmost importance to us.

We understand that you are providing us with your personal information and that it is vital for us to earn your trust to provide our services to you effectively. 

We believe it is our responsibility to protect your personal information. The services we provide are based on preserving your anonymity until you choose to disclose further personal details. 

We will never sell or rent your personal information to third parties. We release personal information only with your permission (including as outlined below in this Privacy Policy), or when we believe release is appropriate for legal compliance and law enforcement (such as to government agencies with statutory law enforcement responsibilities); to facilitate court proceedings; enforce or apply our terms and conditions; or to protect the rights or safety of our users or others. We have designed a thorough privacy policy with these things in mind. 

If you have any questions regarding our privacy policy, we encourage you to contact our privacy officer through our contact form. 

This privacy policy was last updated on 5th June 2014. 

Collection and use of your information __

FindSomeone collects personal information about you through your use of the Services and the Website. FindSomeone may use this personal information to help us provide the Services to you, to verify your identity, to enforce or apply our terms and conditions, to protect the rights, property, or safety of FindSomeone, our users, or others, for internal research purposes, for promoting and marketing other FindSomeone products and Services to you, and for any other use that you authorise. 

There are various kinds of information we collect about you: 

  1. #### Private information that you provide us

You are required to provide us with certain personal information, such as your name and email address, to help us provide a safe service and, if required, verify your identity when you contact us. Your private information will never be sold to any other party and will never be disclosed by us on FindSomeone without your explicit permission. 

  2. #### Public information that you enter for your profile

You are encouraged to provide a lot of information about yourself for your profile to help find people to meet. You may update this information at any time. All information you provide for your profile should be considered public as any internet user can conceivably find this information. 

Members may also have the ability to see which other members have viewed their profile and saved them as a favourite. 

We provide settings to allow you to restrict visibility of your profile and visibility of any photos you upload. If you select "show my photos to anyone" your photo (and profile) may also appear in the FindSomeone newsletter. If you wish to remove your profile from the FindSomeone website, you may do this using the "remove my profile" link on your settings page. 

Information collected is designed to minimise the ability for someone to identify you. It is your responsibility to control the extent of information you provide on your FindSomeone profile to help us to ensure your privacy is protected. 

  3. #### Financial information you provide us.

We offer services that require you to provide us with financial information such as your credit card number. We take all reasonable steps to ensure your financial information is securely transmitted and protected. We protect your credit card information during transmission by using the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, which encrypts your information when transmitted over the internet. FindSomeone retains only partial card details. Full card details may be encrypted and securely stored by the payment provider that processes the transaction. You may contact us for further information about this process. 

If you choose to make ongoing payments each month, your credit card details are encrypted and securely stored by the payment provider. 

  4. #### Messages you send to other members.

FindSomeone provides facilities to allow you to send private messages to other members. These messages are private and only visible to the chosen recipient. FindSomeone reserves the right to read any of your messages where we receive complaints from the recipient of a message or have reason to believe that you are in breach of our terms and conditions or code of ethics. 

  5. #### Information provided to customer support.

Messages you send to our customer support team are private between you and our customer support staff and management. 

Any communications from you or from others, relating to your membership or activity on FindSomeone may be stored in a file specific to you. 

Customer service phone conversations may be recorded for internal training and quality assurance purposes. This helps us ensure the information we provide members is consistent and accurate. Phone records will be stored securely and will generally be retained for up to six months. 

  6. #### FindSomeone usage information.

We collect information on your usage of FindSomeone for the purposes of providing and improving our services, researching users' use of FindSomeone, demographics, interests, and behaviour, and to better understand and serve you and our community. 

We collect information about the features you use and pages you visit on FindSomeone, the URL that you just came from when you arrive at FindSomeone, the URL you next go to when you leave FindSomeone, your browser and device information, and your IP address. See also the section on "Cookies" below. This information is used by us internally, and to enable features on FindSomeone such as allowing members to see which other members have viewed their profile or saved them as a favourite. 

Users who login have their IP addresses recorded. This information will only be provided to legal authorities in cases of suspected fraud or for law enforcement purposes. This information is stored securely and will not be provided to other members or non-authorised parties. 

If you choose to post messages on our Message Board, we will collect the information you provide. 

FindSomeone may collect data on your current geographical location to support the Who's Near Me feature. This data is only collected upon your authorisation and if your mobile device supports location-based services. Your authorisation can be revoked and your location data deleted at any time via the authorisation page on the mobile site. 

  7. #### FindSomeone and Facebook

You can access your Facebook information through FindSomeone. This may include logging in to FindSomeone with your Facebook credentials or importing your Facebook profile information and photos into your FindSomeone profile. FindSomeone will not access your information from Facebook without your express permission. However, when you grant permission you are authorising FindSomeone to collect, store, retain and use indefinitely, any and all information that you agreed Facebook could provide to FindSomeone through the Facebook application programming interface. 

If you no longer wish to use Facebook in conjunction with FindSomeone, you can remove our access through your Facebook account, or contact us for more information. 

Email communication __

We will not disclose your email address to other members of FindSomeone. In the event that you are sent a message from another member we may (depending on your settings) notify you that you have a message waiting. When sending a message to another member through FindSomeone, your registered email address will not be made available to the message recipient. 

We use your email address to allow us to operate our services. This includes sending you emails relating to our services, notifications of messages from other members and other related communication. 

We have a policy of enabling you to control the emails you receive and to opt-out of particular types of messages at any time. You can also change your notification settings through your Settings page 

Control of your password __

You are responsible for protecting your login details (your email address and password). Do not disclose this information to third parties. If you choose to share your login details with third-parties for other services, you are responsible for all actions taken with this information. We strongly recommend using different passwords on different sites and that you review the privacy policy of any parties to whom you provide an email address and password. 

FindSomeone will never ask you for your address or password by email. 

Cookies __

Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by your web browser in a file on your computer's hard drive when you use our website. We use cookies to deliver information and fresh content specific to your interests and to improve the experience of using our site. Cookies are widely used on most major websites. 

FindSomeone uses "session" cookies to temporarily store information to help you use the site. This information is used to deliver the right content to you as you use the site and avoids unnecessarily asking you to log in. Session cookies expire immediately when you close your web browser or are deleted after a period of no activity on FindSomeone. 

FindSomeone also uses "persistent" cookies to personalise the user experience, to help protect our members and to provide us with research information (such as how often members visit FindSomeone each month). Persistent cookies allow us to identify users and assist us in identifying any abuse of the FindSomeone service. A persistent auto-login cookie is also stored when Members select the "remember me" option when logging in. The auto-login cookie is removed when the Member logs out. 

FindSomeone also participates in Google's AdWords pay-per-click advertising programme. AdWords advertisements appear on Google's search result pages and on the Google Network. Google uses cookies to measure the number of Google users that click on an advertisement and visit certain FindSomeone web pages, or who complete certain actions on the Website (such as upgrading to Gold membership). Google provides this data to FindSomeone without identifying the users. [View Google's privacy policy](http://www.google.com/policies/privacy/). 

Advertising and third party links __

Some FindSomeone advertisers may request information directly from users, or link to sites that do so. FindSomeone has no control over its advertisers' privacy policies, and encourages users to review such policies prior to submitting any personal information to them. 

FindSomeone contains non-advertising links to a variety of third party sites to enhance the member experience. FindSomeone has no control of either the content or privacy policies of such sites, nor should such links be considered an endorsement of these sites except where otherwise noted.FindSomeone uses "session" cookies to temporarily store information to help you use the site. This information is used to deliver the right content to you as you use the site and avoids unnecessarily asking you to log in. Session cookies expire immediately when you close your web browser or are deleted after a period of no activity on FindSomeone. 

In some cases, third party advertisers may also use cookies in certain advertisements that appear on the website for advertising purposes. 

FindSomeone also uses Google's DoubleClick services to deliver display advertisements intended to be relevant to your interests, based on the information you have provided to us through the use of any of our Services. We do not provide your personal information to Google.Fiere are various kinds of information we collect about you: 

Nielsen Online - NZ internet statistics __

FindSomeone, like most large New Zealand websites, uses the Nielsen Online counting system to collect information such as the number of visitors per day or the number of pages requested per day. To do this, FindSomeone has a small piece of code on each page which counts these statistics. This enables us to see where we are in the 'top 10' list of New Zealand websites. 

For more information, view the [Nielsen Online privacy policy](http://www.nielsen-online.com/privacy.jsp?section=leg_scs). 

Trade Me uses [Google Analytics](http://www.google.com/analytics/) and [Mixpanel](https://mixpanel.com/) to better understand the behaviour of Findsomeone members using our website and mobile platforms, and to improve our service. For example, it helps us to identify how many members visit a particular page, and what those users do on that page. 

For more information, view Google Analytics' information on [safeguarding your data](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en) and the [Mixpanel privacy policy](https://mixpanel.com/privacy/). 

Updates to our information practices __

From time to time, we make changes to our information practices or alter the functionality of FindSomeone. We always update this statement accordingly, so we encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on privacy practices at FindSomeone. Your continued use of FindSomeone represents your acceptance of this Privacy Policy as amended.
